ADEOLU OYINLOLA

https://github.com/deoluoyinlola
https://linkedin.com/in/deoluoyinlola/
https://deoluoyinlola.netlify.app/

(+234)7035554522 6, Omotara Strt, Agbowo, UI. Ibadan deoluovinlola@gmail.com

SUMMARY

• **Software Developer** - Front-end developer that is passionate to accelerate the development of software projects and teams.

I have 3 years of experience in project planning, executing, monitoring and controlling, 4 years of running startup and 2 years in logistics planning.

SKILLS/EXPERTISE

- Languages & Technologies HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Tailwind, Git, GitHub, Product Design UI/UX (Figma), Slack, Discord.
- Others Project Management Professional Certified, HSE Level 2, Transport Planning, CorelDraw.

CAREER HIGHLIGHT

- Personal website Build a personal website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- gbera.ng Designing and developing on-demand logistics web app using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
 User can request truck and accept truck for cargo delivery.
- ruralx.africa Building a web app, using React JS that display agricultural input and produce price from the real-time API. User can view, list and search for price of specific agricultural input or produce.
- Team lead and instrumental to secured jumia.com's 3PL contract for a foremost mobility startup in Nigeria.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Developer, Ibadan Nigeria - Front-end Developer

Oct. 2021 – present

• Am currently working as a freelancer at Upwork. Where I have built websites app using languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Js to customers specification. I learnt the skills of finding, managing clients on freelancer platforms.

SideHustle Internship 4.0, Nigeria - Intern

Oct. 2021

• For the six weeks, I learned about responsive website design and web application with the use of Tailwind, JavaScript also applying the knowledge to solve real-life projects.

Metro Africa Xpress(max.ng), Lagos Nigeria - Hub Manager

Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2016

- Responsible for managing and coordinating all activities within the hub.
- Monitored the flow of parcels and cash with help of web application; delivery module.
- Ensured customer's goods in accordance with best practices are rightly delivered on time with 95% customer satisfaction.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Millenium Development Goals (MDGs), Onna, Akwa Ibom - Secretary

June 2015 - Oct. 2015

- Record and draft meeting's agenda, set goals on crucial actions.
- Sensitized market woman on goal of MDGs, other forms of social enterprise development schemes, discover some of the challenges of rural woman and best practices to handle them.
- Educate the senior science school students on national value, goal setting and achievements.

National Association of Sepeteri Student, LAUTECH Chapter - President

Aug. 2011 - June 2012

- Facilitate student's bursary at local government levels for all qualify students.
- Organized symposiums lectures and careers programs for all the fresher of Sepeteri origin.
- Excellent conflict resolution skills in the events of misunderstanding among students.

EDUCATION

MDN Web Docs – Web Development

(*Nov. 2021 – present*)

■ Course: Learn Web Development

The Odin Project – Frontend Development

(*Oct.* 2021 – *present*)

Course: Foundations, Full Stack JavaScript

FreeCodeCamp – Web Design

(Sept. 2021 - Nov. 2021)

Course: Responsive Web Design Certification

Project Management Institute, Akwa Ibom Nigeria – PMI Certified

(Feb. 2015 – July 2015)

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomoso Nigeria – B.Tech, Transport Management (*Sept. 2008 – April 2013*)